MELINDA IVANOV

Bellevue, WA (425) 614-5541 jns.melinda@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/melinda-ivanov jnsmelinda.github.io/

Technical-minded developer leveraging MSc degree in earth sciences from University of Szeged and earned full-stack web development certificate at University of Washington where honed skills in JavaScript, React, Node.js and MySQL, MongoDB and gained special interest in server-side technologies. Experience includes taking responsibilities in design, technical, and development decisions in academic projects using newly developed skills. Passionate problem solver, aiming to deliver quality products by applying clean design/coding principles and following agile methodologies. Fast learner who is enthusiastic about innovative techniques and excited to leverage skills as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Java, Ruby, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Tools and Technologies: **React, OOP**, Spring Boot, Express, Ajax, **MySQL, MongoDB**, Lombok, Gradle, Bootstrap, JSP, Thymeleaf, IntelliJ IDEA, RubyMine, Atom, VS Code, JGrasp, **Git**, GitHub, GitLab, Excel, Word, Power Point, Heroku Modeling and Simulation: GIS, QGIS, ArcGIS, ESRI, StatGraphics, WinGslib, VarioWin, Surpher, Grapher, Mapping

MOST RECENT PROJECTS

<u>DISASTER DASHBOARD</u>: This group project encompasses a full-stack development project utilizing the MERN Stack. This app is built to collect recent disasters, near earth events, COVID-19 Statistics, the Silver and Gold price and a checklist allowing to verify the items needed to survive a disaster. Contributions include building out the disaster events and checklist, with server side and data management utilizing JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, MySQL, MVC, OKTA, App: https://cryptic-castle-46514.herokuapp.com

Source: https://github.com/jnsmelinda/Disaster Dashboard

<u>GOOGLE BOOK SEARCH</u>: This Interactive app allows the user to search for books and save them to the reading-list or view them on google. When the book has been read, it can be deleted from the reading-list. JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Google Books API, React, HTML5, CSS3, App: https://protected-island-24963.herokuapp.com/#/ Source: https://github.com/jnsmelinda/Google-Book-Search

<u>VENT</u>: Key contributor of this group project to build an interactive website to help concerned citizens to see the air quality in their area and to provide a platform where they are able to express their feelings alongside a short message to their local representative regarding the air quality. Responsibilities include building out the server-side technologies and data management utilizing Node.js, JavaScript, MySQL, JQuery, Ajax, APIs, Sequelize, ORM,

App: https://vent-airquality-tracker.herokuapp.com Source: https://github.com/jnsmelinda/Vent

EDUCATION

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE 05.2020 - 12.2020 - University of Washington, 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Express, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, MongoDB, Git, GitHub, GitLab, RESTful APIs, Responsive Design, OOP, MERN stack

EARTH SCIENTIST MSc 06.2015 Geology major, 4.00 GPA, University of Szeged, Hungary - Academic studies in Statistics, Advanced mathematics, 2D/3D Modelling and Simulation, Geospatial data analysis, Geophysics, Technical Geology EARTH SCIENTIST BSc 06.2013 Geology major, University of Szeged, Hungary - Academic studies in Mapping, Mathematics, GIS, Data collection and calculations, Materials Science

EXPERIENCE

KEY HOLDER 2017 - 2018, The Body Shop, Bellevue WA

- Successfully designing and implementing daily strategic sales plans
- Top performer at customer satisfaction and client management
- Coach of team members to ensure best team performance, resulting in 10% revenue

SALES ASSOCIATE 2016 - 2017, Bath & Body Works, Bellevue WA

- Passionate team player building strong customer relationships
- Constantly exceeding personal sales goals by 30%

INTERN 07.2014 - 08.2014, Nonprofit Environmental Management Ltd. Szeged, Hungary

- Participating in a collaboration between the University of Szeged and Nonprofit Environmental Management Ltd. of Szeged, researching the urban vegetation and its effects on the urban climate.
- Field data collection and computerization using MS Excel

TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST 2012 - 2013, Telecom (contract via Melo-Depo 2000), Szeged, Hungary

- Bilingual technical support related to all IT platforms
- Top 10% performer at customer satisfaction

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Authorized to work in the US for any employer (permanent resident)
- Full working proficiency in English
- Native proficiency in Hungarian